Guide to the Harriet Doerr Papers, 1976-1996
Department of Special Collections
Harriet Doerr Papers,
1976-1996
Special Collections M0668
Doerr, Harriet.
18.25 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Harriet Doerr, 1993, 1994, and 1996.
Biography
Harriet Doerr was born in Pasadena, California, in 1910. She has lived much of her life in Mexico and now resides in her hometown. Educated at Smith College and Stanford University in the late 1920s, she returned to Stanford in 1977 to earn a bachelor's degree and do graduate work in fiction writing. With the help of a Wallace Stegner Fellowship at Stanford, she wrote her first novel, Stones for Ibarra, which is set in Mexico. This book won numerous awards, among them the National Book Award for a First Work of Fiction, and has also been adapted as a film for television. She has published short stories in periodicals such as The New York Times and Atlantic. One such story, "Edie: A Life," appeared in the O. Henry Awards Prize Stories and Best American Short Stories. Harriet Doerr has also published three more books, Consider This, Señora, another novel set in Mexico, and Under an Aztec Sun and The Tiger in the Grass, two collections of short stories.
Scope and Content
The Harriet Doerr Papers contain materials from many of her published works including Stones for Ibarra, Consider This, Señora, Under an Aztec Sun, and The Tiger in the Grass. Comments and criticisms of the stories which make up the novels, as well as manuscripts prior to publication, may also be found in the collection. Also included are many short stories which were not included in her books or remain unpublished. Many of the stories were begun as writing exercises for creative writing classes Doerr took from author and Stanford professor, John L'Heureux. His critiques and comments can be found throughout the collection. Ephemera concerning interviews, talks, and book signings by Doerr are included from her personal collections. A segment is devoted to the Hallmark TV film of Stones for Ibarra, including scripts, photographs, and reviews. Newspaper clippings and magazine articles describing her success as an author make up another large part of the collection. Several boxes in the original accession and the addition are comprised of correspondence to Doerr from individuals praising her writing and success, as well as professional correspondence concerning books and stories published. Finally, it is interesting to note that Doerr included several computer disks apparently containing drafts of stories, both in the original accession and the addition.
Arrangement
The three original accessions of the Harriet Doerr Papers (93-119, 94-025, 94-038) were not organized into definitive series. However, logical organization is apparent and could possibly come under the following headings:
Consider This, Señora
Stones for Ibarra
Miscellaneous Stories
Albert Guerard Corrections
Manuscripts and Translations
Interviews and Talks
Correspondence
Hallmark TV Film of Stones for Ibarra
Newsclippings and Magazine Articles
The addition to the existing Doerr Papers (accession 1996-068), which starts on page 8, is organized into the following series:
I. The Tiger in the Grass (including stories, Mss, etc.)
II. Consider This, Señora (including stories, corrections, and reviews)
III. Stones for Ibarra (title pages, last chapter)
IV. Miscellaneous Short Stories (including class comments and corrections)
V. Readings, Signings, and Promotionals
VI. Professional Correspondence
VII. General Correspondence
VIII. Computer Disks
Access Terms
Abrahams, Billy.; Adams, Alice, 1926-; Austin, Reid.; Davenport, Marcia, 1903-; Gaines, Ernest J., 1933-; Guérard, Albert J. (Albert Joseph), 1914-; Kroll, Ernest.; L'Heureux, John.; Miller, Clive.; Munro, Grant.; American literature--20th century.
Container List
- Original papers, materials from Accessions, 1993-119, 1994-025, 1994-038
  - Consider This, Señora: Book Jacket Designs (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Consider This, Señora, Chronology (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Consider This, Señora, Katherine Andres - notes, revisions (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Consider This, Señora, Dedication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Early Stories with comments by Clive Miller: Untitled (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Early Stories with comments by Clive Miller, "Please," "Letters from Mexico," "400 block, 3:30pm" (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Early Stories with comments by Clive Miller, "Visitors" (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Early Stories with comments by Clive Miller, "Solitary Confinement" (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Early Stories with comments by Clive Miller, "The Seasons" (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Early Stories with comments by Clive Miller, "The Picnic in the Wildflowers" (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Early Stories with comments by Clive Miller, "A Little Kiss" (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Early Stories with comments by Clive Miller, "The Local Train," "Landmarks," "Notes from a Mexican Village," "At the Villa" (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Early Stories with comments by Clive Miller, "You May Wait in a Private Room" (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Early Stories with comments by Clive Miller, "Carnations" (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Early Stories with comments by Clive Miller, "The Christmas Centerpiece," "The Extinguishing of Aunt Alice," "First Find All the White Pieces" (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Early Stories with comments by Clive Miller, "Handling Time," "The Local Train" (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Early Stories with comments by Clive Miller, "The Wax Flowers" (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Early Stories with comments by Clive Miller, "Loreto," "Lunch with the Bishop," "Wetback," "Take it One Day at a Time," "Humiliation" (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Yolla Bolly Press: Under the Aztec Sun (galley proofs) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Stanford Sequoia, 1987:"Ibarra: Pages from a Notebook" (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Stones for Ibarra (stories): comments by Billy Abrahams, Alice Adams, and Ernest Gaines (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Comments by John L'Heureux: "Wetback," "Visitors," "Kid Muñoz," "The Local Train," "At the Villa," "First Find all the White Pieces," "Landmarks" (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Comments by John L'Heureux, "The Baptists," "Immense Distances, Extraordinary Events," "Loreto," "Lunch with the Bishop," "Parts of Speech" (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Comments by John L'Heureux, "Calling from Loreto" (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Comments by John L'Heureux, "The Priests' Picnic," "The Red Taxi" (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "Picnic at Amapolas": class comments (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Picnic at Amapolas", final versions (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Easter Weekend": revised and final versions (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Goya and the Widow Bowles": original (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "Goya and the Widow Bowles", revised and final versions (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "A Over Middle C": revised and final versions (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "Truckloads of Tuberoses": revisions (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Another Short day in La Luz": revised and final versions (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "Bud on the Side of the Angels": revised and final versions (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "Exit the Widow": comments and final version (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Writing Course by John L'Heureux: Comments, Examination, Essay (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "The Bandstand at the Square": comments and revisions (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "As it Happened": comments and revisions (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Catalogue: Harcourt Brace Jovanovich Publishers, spring 1993 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - VUELTA (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Submitted to the Henfield Foundation: "The Red Taxi," "The Baptists," "The Doctor of the Moon" (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Stones for Ibarra: class comments on stories (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "The Evertons out of Their Minds": comments and revisions (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - "A Clear Understanding": comments and revisions (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - "The Life Sentence of Jose Reyes": comments, revisions, and final versions (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - "Kid Muñoz"; revisions and final version (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - "The Inheritance": comments and revisions (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "Pray for Us, Fathers": revisions (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - "Pray for Us, Fathers", comments and revisions (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - "The Red Taxi": last revisions and final (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - "Parts of Speech": comments and revisions (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - "Parts of Speech": comments and revisions (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - "The Thorn on the Blown-Glass Lamp": comments and revisions (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "The Night of September Fifteenth" (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - "Christmas Messages": comments and revisions (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - "Lunch with the Bishop": comments and revisions (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - "Calling from Loreto": comments and revisions (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - "The Priests' Picnic": comments and revisions (Box 5a, Folder 1)
  - "The Priests' Picnic": comments and revisions (Box 5a, Folder 2)
  - "The Baptists": class comments (Box 5a, Folder 3)
  - "The Doctor of the Moon": comments and revisions (Box 5a, Folder 4)
  - "The Doctor of the Moon": comments and revisions (Box 5a, Folder 5)
  - "Immense Distances, Extraordinary Events": comments and revisions (Box 5a, Folder 6)
  - "Immense Distances, Extraordinary Events": comments and revisions (Box 5a, Folder 7)
  - "Bring Stones," "To Know Its Ways" (Box 5a, Folder 8)
  - "Bring Stones": comments (Box 5a, Folder 9)
  - Albert Guerard Corrections: "The Local Train" (Box 5b, Folder 1)
  - Albert Guerard Corrections, "A Clear Understanding" (Box 5b, Folder 2)
  - Albert Guerard Corrections, "Parts of Speech" (Box 5b, Folder 3)
  - Albert Guerard Corrections, "The Priests' Picnic" (Box 5b, Folder 4)
  - Albert Guerard Corrections, "Immense Distances, Extraordinary Events" (Box 5b, Folder 5)
  - Albert Guerard Corrections, "The Life Sentence of Jose Reyes" (Box 5b, Folder 6)
  - Albert Guerard Corrections, "The Inheritance" (Box 5b, Folder 7)
  - Albert Guerard Corrections, "Lunch with the Bishop" (Box 5b, Folder 8)
  - Albert Guerard Corrections, "The Baptists" (Box 5b, Folder 9)
  - Albert Guerard Corrections, "Pray for Us, Fathers" (Box 5b, Folder 10)
  - Albert Guerard Corrections: "The Doctor of the Moon" (Box 5b, Folder 11)
  - New Fiction Catalog: Harcourt Brace (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Consider This, Señora: editorial suggestions by Katherine Andres (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Stones for Ibarra: Mss (cover page - p.84) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Stones for Ibarra, (pp. 85-213) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Consider This, Señora: Mss with corrections (a) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Consider This, Señora, Mss with corrections (b) (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Consider This, Señora, Galley revisions, (title page - p.68) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Consider This, Señora, Galley revisions (p.69-end) (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Stones for Ibarra: French translation by Pascale Hubert Liebler (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Stones for Ibarra, galley (iii - p.69) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Stones for Ibarra, galley (p. 70-160) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Stones for Ibarra, galley (p.161-220) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Stones for Ibarra, galley (p.221-278) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Stones for Ibarra, Notes and correspondence re. Manuscript sent to Viking Press (includes characters and chronology) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Stones for Ibarra, Viking Press Manuscript (copy): (title page - p.69) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Stones for Ibarra, Viking Press Manuscript (copy), (p. 70-145) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Stones for Ibarra, Viking Press Manuscript (copy), (p.146-220) (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Stones for Ibarra, Viking Press Manuscript (copy), (p.221-278) (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Stones for Ibarra: Correspondences re. Spanish translation (Box 8a, Folder 1)
  - Stones for Ibarra, Spanish translation: Ch.I - Ch.VI (Box 8a, Folder 2)
  - Stones for Ibarra, Spanish translation, Ch.VII - Ch.X (Box 8a, Folder 3)
  - Stones for Ibarra, Spanish translation, Ch.XI - Ch.XVII (Box 8a, Folder 4)
  - Letters re. French Publication: Thierry de Navacelle, Michel Deguy (Box 8a, Folder 5)
  - Consider This, Señora: galley (title page - p.65) (Box 8a, Folder 6)
  - Consider This, Señora, galley (p. 66-131) (Box 8a, Folder 7)
  - Consider This, Señora, galley (p.132-222) (Box 8a, Folder 8)
  - Consider This, Señora, Corrections by John L'Heureux of text (title page - p.65) (Box 8a, Folder 9)
  - Consider This, Señora, Corrections by John L'Heureux of text, (p. 66-155) (Box 8a, Folder 10)
  - Consider This, Señora, Corrections by John L'Heureux of text, (p.156-246) (Box 8a, Folder 11)
  - Consider This, Señora, Cork Smith corrections of text (title page - p.65) (Box 8a, Folder 12)
  - Consider This, Señora, Cork Smith corrections of text, (p. 66-155) (Box 8a, Folder 13)
  - Consider This, Señora, Cork Smith corrections of text, (p.156-246) (Box 8a, Folder 14)
  - Harcourt Brace: Correspondence and computer disk (Box 8b, Folder 1)
  - Consider This, Señora: Repro Dupe (title page - p.194) (Box 8b, Folder 2)
  - Consider This, Señora, Repro Dupe (p.195-240) (Box 8b, Folder 3)
  - Consider This, Señora, Proof (title page - p.49) (Box 8b, Folder 4)
  - Consider This, Señora, Proof, (p. 50-139) (Box 8b, Folder 5)
  - Consider This, Señora, Proof, (p.140-222) (Box 8b, Folder 6)
  - Consider This, Señora: Repro Dupe (title page - p.100) (Box 8b, Folder 7)
  - Consider This, Señora, Repro Dupe, (p.101-241) (Box 8b, Folder 8)
  - Consider This, Señora, Master Galley (p. 1-55) (Box 8b, Folder 9)
  - Consider This, Señora, Master Galley, (p. 56-110) (Box 8b, Folder 10)
  - Consider This, Señora, Master Galley, (p.111-170) (Box 8b, Folder 11)
  - Interview (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Pen West: Wallace Stegner (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - The National Undergraduate Literature Conference: Ogden, UT- 4/13/90 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Pasadena Weekly, 6/13/86 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Tell Me a Story (public radio), Marjorie Leet (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Katherine Henderson, Univ. of Kentucky (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Friends of CalTech Libraries (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - KCET: Take Five, 11/27/89 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - SCRIPPS College Talk (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Talks: Old Mill, Polytechnic, The Wednesday Club (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Telephone interview with Jim Pappas: 1/9/85(Penguin Contemporary Authors Series) (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Santa Barbara Writer's Conference (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Talks (1984):Town Club, Parachutists, Pasadena Public Library, Pasadena Arts Council, Williams Book Store, San Francisco State Univ. (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Invitations to speak: declined or pending (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Pasadena City College: 5/4/85 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Southern California Booksellers (10/12/84); San Diego and Southern California Booksellers Association (9/6/84) (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Bookstores: readings, signings (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Pasadena Public Library; Pasadena 100th Anniversary, Friends of the San Marino Public Library (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Literary Women's Conference; Malibu Public Library; PEN, LA Center (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Literary Women, Long Beach: 1/19/85 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Radio: KCRW (Connie Goldman) (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Sacred Heart Preparatory (4/29/86); Stanford University Bookstore (4/30/86); Stanford University, CROW (4/30/86) (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - The Music Center Book Fair Panel (6/8/86) (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Declined Interviews and talks (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Writers at work: Salt Lake City, Park City (July 10-14, 1985) (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Purdue (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Syracuse University (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Cornell University: Kenneth McClare (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - University of California, Santa Barbara: 11/7/85 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - University of Iowa (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Notes for talks (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Pasadena Smith Club: 10/18/87:Valley Hunt (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Brandeis University National Women's Committee: Beverly Wilshire Hotel, 11/6/86 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - SCRIPPS talk: 10/10/86 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Jim Krusoe: Santa Monica Writers Workshop, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Invitations to speak: declined or postponed (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Reed College; California State University at Northridge; Multnomah County Library (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - University of Arizona: 10/11/87 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - CalTech (Friends of the Library): 12/8/89 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Reed College; Multnomah County Library (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - U.C. Berkeley Women Writers at Work: 11/11/89 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Cerritos College, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - UCLA (3/90); LA City College (5/89) (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Radio & TV interviews (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - The Writer; Fiction Network Magazine (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Friends of Mexico; Manhattan Theater Club 1990 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Writers at Work Conference, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - "Fiction at the Folger," & LA Times article, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Westridge Alumnae Reunion Day, 4/89 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Proceedings (Series II, no.36): American Academy & Institute of Arts and Letters (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Commonwealth Club of California, San Francisco, 6/14/85 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - PEN/Faulkner Award for Fiction, 5/85 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Bay Area Book Reviewers Awards, 3/15/85 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - National Book Critics Award: nomination (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - The American Book Award (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - The LA Times Book Review, 9/23/84 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - "Hope and Despair in Contemporary American Culture...," Bruce McIver, "A Voice of One's Own: Contemporary Short Fiction...," Ann Harleman Stewart (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Requests for blurbs (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Requests to write (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - The National Book Foundation (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: 1980-1983 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1/84 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2/84 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 3/84 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 4/84 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, May - Sept., 1984 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Oct. - Dec., 1984 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Jan. - Feb., 1985 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, March - May, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, June - Aug., 1985 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Sept. - Dec., 1985 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Jan. - April, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: May - Dec., 1986 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, No Date (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, "Picnic at Amapolas," (Spring, 1986):Answered (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Copies of letters: 4/18/86-9/4/86 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Reading Groups (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Letters, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Letters (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Letters: Reid Austin, Ernest Kroll, Grant Munro, Marcia Davenport (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Letters and answers (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Copies of letters: 8/22/84-3/4/86 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Letters to Press (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Pictures - Hallmark: Arizona, 11/87 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Stones for Ibarra: Titus Productions, Hallmark - Early Script Suggestions (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Hallmark Promotional (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Hallmark Pictures (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Tucson (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Stones for Ibarra: TV Script (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Stones for Ibarra, Final script (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Stones for Ibarra, Cast, Shooting schedule (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Stones for Ibarra, Cast & revisions (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Stones for Ibarra, USA Today (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Best Seller Lists (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Pasadena Weekly: Larry Wilson (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Peninsula Times Tribune; Palo Alto Weekly, Stanford Daily (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Newsclippings (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Los Angeles Times (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Newsclippings: San Francisco, Oakland, San Jose (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Newsclippings, Palo Alto Weekly (Dec. 1979, 1981) (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Newsclippings (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Newsclippings, Los Angeles (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous: reviews, correspondence (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Mexico City News (Morelia) (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - The Cresset (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Newsclippings: Los Angeles Times (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous newsclippings (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Best Seller lists (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Interviews (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - American Academy of Arts & Letters: 5/85 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Newsclippings: New York Times (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Westridge School (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - American Academy & Institute of Arts and Letters (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - The New Yorker: 12/24/90, 2/17/86 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - The Sequoia: Winter, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - The Ark River Review: vol.5:2 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Newsclippings: San Jose Mercury News, Pasadena Star News (Earthquake) (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - From Aida Ferrarone: Noticias del Mundo (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Pending: Ann Gardner (film) (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Hallmark: Stones for Ibarra (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - CBS Broadcast Group (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Yolla Bolly Press: Under the Aztec Sun (1) (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Yolla Bolly Press: Under the Aztec Sun (2) (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Yolla Bolly Press: Under the Aztec Sun (3) (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Publicity (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Contemporary American Fiction (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Publicity: Viking, Penguin (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Viking Promotion (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous clippings (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - The Atlantic, 4/91 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - The Los Angeles Times Magazine, 7/2/89 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Ladies Home Journal, 7/85 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Quarterly West, Autumn 1978 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - The Hudson Review, Autumn 1984 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Image, 5/3/87 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Magazine, Spring 1989 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - The Book of the Month Club News, 4/88 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Peninsula, 3/87 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - California, 1/84 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Ms., 1/84 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Vanity Fair, 1/84 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - The New Yorker, 1/16/84 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Mademoiselle, 2/84 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Mature Outlook, Fall 1984 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Vogue, 12/83 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - The New Republic, 1/30/84 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - The New Yorker, 12/24/84(p.31) (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - The New York Times book review (Box 18, Folder NF)
  - The Book Review: The Los Angeles Times (Box 18, Folder NF)
  - The Christian Science Monitor (Box 18, Folder NF)
- Adenda, materials received 4/30/96, Accession 96-068
  - Series I: The Tiger in the Grass (published 1995)
    - "The Tiger in the Grass": corrections and revisions (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - "The Tiger in the Grass", final draft (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - "The Tiger in the Grass", background research (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - "Please" (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - "Flowering Stick" (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - "From Paris to Savigny-sur-Seille" (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - "Carnations" (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - "The Christmas Centerpiece" (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - "The Extinguishing of Great Aunt Alice" (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - "Low Tide at Four" (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - "Like Heaven" (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - "Seasons" (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - "Local Train" (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - "The Watchman at the Gate" (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - "Way Stations": early versions and revisions (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - "Way Stations", later versions and O'Henry copy (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - "Saint's Day": class comments (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - "Saint's Day": class comments (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - "Consider This, Señora" (later "Sun, Pure Air, and a View"): comments by class, L'Heureux (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - "Consider This, Señora" (later "Sun, Pure Air, and a View"): comments by class, L'Heureux (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - "Consider This, Señora" (later "Sun, Pure Air, and a View"): later versions (Box 20, Folder 5)